AMAD UDDIN

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER ♣ +923334949086

• DETAILS •

Lahore, Pakistan +923334949086 amad.aud@gmail.com

LINKS

Portfolio

LinkedIn

Stackoverflow

SKILLS

Django, DRF, Channels

Python

Angular 10, Angular Universal

React, Redux

Bootstrap, Material

Selenium, Scrappy, Beautiful soap

Node.js, Nextjs

JavaScript

Typescript

AWS, Cognito, EC2, ECS

PostgreSQL, Redis, AWS Aurora

HTML, CSS, SCSS

Git, CI/CD

Docker, Docker Swarm

Unit Test

Google Cloud Services, Heroku

JIRA, Trello, Grafana

Stripe, GPay, WeChat Pay

Sentry, Mailchimp

LANGUAGES

English

Urdu

PROFILE

I am a software developer with over 5 years of experience developing and implementing cutting-edge software solutions to improve corporate productivity. I typically focus on moving concepts into development and making sure the project does not fall behind schedule through sprint planning and continuous integration techniques.

EXPERIENCE

Team Lead & Fullstack developer at Hailu Tech Pvt, Lahore

July 2019 — Present

- · Worked directly with client to assist in a variety of analytics and software projects
- Recruited and directed a team of 12 developers.
- Developed 3 different products from scratch in cutting edge technologies.
- · Worked on Angular 10, Django, Python, WebRTC and AWS.
- Re-design the project that have 60k+ active users and make the onboarding process easy for new customers.
- Monitored the performance of team members and worked to increase the productivity.
- Leveraged Django backend technologies that integrated with React using SSR and Next.JS
- Learned AWS to assist in external dev-ops projects such as setting up automated test cases with code commits
- Participate and lead the scrum daily stand up meetings, Sprint planning and scrum retrospective meetings.

Fullstack developer at Septem System, Lahore

August 2018 — July 2019

- Worked directly with clients for user stories.
- Developed a centralized delivery network system that is successfully deployed.
- Developed a cloud infrastructure (IAAS) using Docker, Docker Swarm.
- Worked with 3 different clients and successfully completed their products.
- Consistently met with an outside contractor to collaborate on development and integration of outside libraries into the current product line.

Software Engineer at Brainplow, Lahore

April 2017 — August 2018

- Worked on products that was owned by the company.
- Improve performance of PostgreSQL queries and explore the indexing in details.
- Worked with a team of 3 engineers to stabilize and enhance products efficiency.

EDUCATION

B.S. Computer Science, FAST - National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences (NUCES), PMNICT Scholership

July 2013 — June 2017

CERTIFICATES

AWS Cloud Practitioner

2022